We all know the importance of education.
我们都知道教育的重要性。
Everyone aspires to have a good one, but its quality and availability is not the same for all.
每个人都渴望接受良好的教育，但教育的质量与是否可以接受教育却因人而异。
This situation changes as social, economic and political conditions change and technological development provides new benefits and threats.
随着社会、经济、政治环境的变化，再加上技术发展带来的新益处与新挑战，这种情况也在不断改变。
The Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD), which promotes policies that will improve the economic and social well-being of people around the world, has been looking at the future of global education.
经济合作与发展组织（经合组织）一直致力于推动各类政策，以提升全球人民的经济与社会福祉，该组织目前正在研究全球教育的未来发展趋势。
Its head of education, Andreas Schleicher, has been talking to the BBC about some major international trends affecting education systems around the world.
其教育部门负责人安德烈亚斯·施莱歇尔在接受英国广播公司采访时，谈到了影响全球教育体系的几大国际趋势。
One threat is the widening gap between rich and poor, with more intense pockets of extreme privilege and deprivation.
其中一个挑战是贫富差距的不断扩大，极端特权与极端贫困的群体分化愈发明显。
In OECD countries, the richest 10% have incomes 10 times greater than the poorest 10%.
在经合组织成员国中，最富有的10%人群的收入是最贫穷的10%人群的十倍。
This inequality is a challenge for schools who want to offer equal and fair access to education for everyone.
这种不平等现象，对致力于为所有人提供平等、公平教育机会的学校而言，是一项巨大挑战。
Another trend is the rising affluence in Asia.
另一个趋势是亚洲地区富裕程度的不断提升。
It's suggested that a large rise in the middle-classes in China and India will increase demand for university places.
有观点认为，中国和印度的中产阶级规模大幅扩大，将会增加对大学入学名额的需求。
Andreas Schleicher asks the question "What values will these newly wealthy consumers want from their schools?"
安德烈亚斯·施莱歇尔提出了这样一个问题：“这些新晋富裕群体希望从学校中获得怎样的价值观？”
Increasing migration will also have an impact on education systems.
移民人数的不断增加也会对教育体系产生影响。
Mobility results in more culturally diverse students eager to learn and develop a good life for themselves.
人口流动带来了更多文化背景多元的学生，这些学生渴望通过学习为自己创造美好的生活。
But that can be a challenge, too, as Andreas Schleicher asks: "How should schools support pupils arriving from around the world?
但这同时也是一项挑战，正如安德烈亚斯·施莱歇尔所提出的：“学校应如何为来自世界各地的学生提供支持？
What questions does it raise about identity and integration?
这会引发哪些关于身份认同与社会融入的问题？
Will schools have a bigger role in teaching about shared values?"
学校在传授共同价值观方面是否应该承担更重要的角色？”
Funding pressure is another issue: as our demand and expectation for education rises and more people go to university, who's going to pay for it all?
资金压力是另一个亟待解决的问题：随着人们对教育的需求与期望不断提升，越来越多的人进入大学深造，那么谁来为这一切买单？
The rise in dependency on technology is another concern.
对技术的依赖程度日益加深也是另一个令人担忧的问题。
What should students learn when many of their talents can be replicated by machines?
当人类的诸多才能都能被机器复刻时，学生们应该学习些什么？
And how reliant should we be on learning from the internet?
我们又该在多大程度上依赖网络学习？
These are just some of the issues the OECD is highlighting.
以上只是经合组织着重强调的部分问题。
But they remain irrelevant for hundreds of millions of the world's poorest children who don't even have access to school places or receive such low-quality education that they leave without the most basic literacy or numeracy.
但对于全球数亿最贫困的儿童来说，这些问题却毫无意义——他们甚至没有入学机会，或是接受的教育质量极低，毕业时连最基础的读写和计算能力都不具备。